Guide to the ILGWU Records, 1884-2006, bulk 1923-1995.
ILGWU Records, 1884-2006, bulk 1923-1995.
- SERIES II. JOINT BOARDS, DISTRICT COUNCILS AND REGIONAL DEPARTMENTS, 1901-2000
  - Subseries A. Joint Boards, 1909-1981
    - 5780/044. Chicago Joint Board records, 1914-1974., Contains files on local unions throughout the Midwestern United States, as well as material on Joint Boards of Milwaukee, St. Louis, and Kansas City. In addition to meeting minutes of several local unions in Chicago (59, 74, 76, 100, 208, 212, 261, 314, 381), this subseries includes minutes of meetings relating to the Chicago Health Center and union health and retirement funds. General correspondence deals with organizing activities in the Midwest area. Subject files consist of correspondence concerning intra-office, union, and local matters, minutes of the Joint Board, and publications either created or collected by the Joint Board. Correspondents throughout both series include Morris Bialis, Abraham Plotkin, Harry Rufer and Harold Schwartz. Locals represented in the records of the Chicago Joint Board include: 67 (Toledo, OH),90 (Elgin, IL), 120 (Decatur, IL), 133 (Peoria, IL), 187 (Racine, WI), 189 (Batavia, IL), 238 (Gary, IN), 240 (Aurora, IL), 272 (Gilman, IL), 277 (Indianapolis, IN), 286 (Ishpeming, MI), 293 (Marquette and Negaunee), 317 (Bay City, MI), 328 (Kokomo, IN) 337 (Elkhart, IN), 354 (Alpena, MI), 355 (Clinton, IA), 355 (Manistee, MI), 364 (Port Huron, MI), 380 (Shelbyville, IN), 382 (Lincoln, IL), 392 (Logansport, IN), 441 (Kalamazoo, MI), 489 (Kendallville, IN), 508 (Mauston, WI).
    - 5780/055. Boston Joint Board records, 1930-1976., Contains meeting minutes and correspondence of the International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union Boston Joint Board, meeting minutes for several Boston local s(12, 46, 46, 73, and 80), as well as the personal correspondence of Philip Kramer.
    - 5780/182. Arbitration proceedings and Joint Board minutes, 1913-1917., This collection contains 24 bound typescript volumes containing proceedings of arbitrations and joint board meetings in the garment industry.
    - 5780/165. Governor Smith's hearings and arbitration with various associations, files, 1924., Consists of records of hearings of the special commission of arbitration on July 15, 1924.
    - 5780/020. New York Cloak Joint Board records, 1926-1973., The New York Cloak Joint Board records consist of articles, correspondence, reports, photographs, and other items. The bulk of the collection is made up of correspondence of three of its managers, Israel Feinberg, Isidore Nagler, and Henoch Mendelsund. There are also some records from the Cloak Out-of-Town Department. These items primarily document concerns of the New York Cloak Joint Board from the 1930 through the 1960s. Much of the material is administrative or routine in nature. Topics addressed include: benefits (especially health insurance and retirement funds); contract negotiations; financial matters; jurisdictional disputes between locals and between the ILGWU and other unions; ILGWU conventions; legal matters; other ILGWU departments and locals; political activity (at both the national and local level); relations with garment manufacturers; union organizing; wages; and worker education. There are also items concerning international labor activities, proposed legislation in the U.S. and in New York State, and aid to Israel.
    - 5780/032. New York Cloak Joint Board minutes, 1926-1977., Contains minutes of the New York Cloak Joint Board, as well as of several of the board’s committees (Retirement Fund, Pension, Executive, Finance, Investment, Rules, Administrative, Appeals, and Special Investigating). Also contains minutes of the Russian Polish Cloak Makers Union and monthly financial reports of the Cloak Joint Board.
    - 5780/041. New York Cloak Joint Board payroll analysis. 1959-1972., Contains the New York Cloak Joint Board’s payroll registers, summaries, and analyses for the years 1959 through 1972.
    - 5780/161. Cloak Joint Board. Governor's Advisory Commission on the Cloak, Suit, and Skirt Industry in New York records, 1924-1959., Contains records relating to New York Governor Smith’s Advisory Commission on the Cloak, Suit, and Skirt Industry in New York, including volumes on the hearings before the commission in 1924 and 1925, reports, and recommendations. Also included is the report of the New York Cloak Joint Board for the years 1956 to 1959.
    - 5780/137. Dress and Cloak Makers Joint Board records, 1933, 1940., This collection consists of news clippings collected by the International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union Dressmakers Joint Board concerning a general strike of August 1933.
    - 5780/033. New York Dress Joint Board minutes, 1922-1976., Includes minutes of Joint Board, Board of Directors, Grievance Committee, Appeal Committee, Health and Welfare Fund, and Retirement Fund meetings.
    - 5780/047. Joint Board Dress and Waistmakers' Union of Greater New York. Managers' correspondence, 1928-1972., Contains the correspondence of the managers of the International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union Joint Board Dress and Waistmakers Union of Greater New York. The correspondents represented are Julius Hochman (manager 1928-1958) and Charles S. Zimmerman (manager, 1958-1972).
    - 5780/164. Joint Board shop lists, 1924-29, 1936-49, 1954., Contains lists of shops with unions included in the Joint Board of Cloak, Skirt, Dress and Reefer Makers’ Unions, the Joint Board of Dress and Waistmakers’ Unions, or the Joint Board of Cloakmakers’ Unions. Also included is a listing of “Manufacturers and Jobbers, Dress Industry,” produced by the Research Department in 1940; the information therein pertains not only to New York City, but to locations across the United States.
    - 5780/048. Cleveland Joint Board records, 1934-1956., Contains correspondence, memoranda, printed material on companies and local unions throughout Ohio, and files on the Los Angeles Joint Board and Philadelphia Joint Board. Also included are files on several Cleveland locals (26, 29, 37, 42, 63, 200, 207, 211), as well as locals in Toledo (67, 368, 466), and Conneaut (175).
    - 5780/174. Cleveland Office records, 1914-1921., Contains reports on arbitration hearings and related material, as well as minutes of the Joint Board of Cloak and Skirt Makers’ Unions.
    - 5780/043. Toronto Dressmakers Joint Council and Toronto Cloak Joint Board records, 1928-1972., Contains records of the Toronto Dressmakers Joint Council and the Toronto Cloak Joint Board, as well as several local unions in Toronto. Locals 14, 72 (Cutters branch; Operators, Finishers, and Drapers branch, Office Committee; Pressers branch; Election Objection Committee), 68, 83, 92, 94, and 192 are represented. Alphabetical files document the activities of the Dressmakers Joint Council and the Cloak Joint Bard, including correspondence of the respective managers, Samuel Kraisman and Joe Macks. Documents include meeting minutes, correspondence, newsletters, reports, financial records, and agreements.
    - 5780/029. Montreal Joint Board minutes, 1945-1968., Contains meeting minutes of Montreal Joint Board’s Board of Directors and the General Executive Board’s Grievance and Appeal Committees, as well as of Local 262 of Montreal. Also included is some correspondence.
    - 5780/030. Montreal Joint Council minutes, 1936-1963., Contains meeting minutes of the Board of Directors and the Grievance and Appeals Committees of the Cloakmakers Union, meeting minutes of the Joint Committee of the Ladies Dress Manufacturing Industry for the Province of Quebec, meeting minutes of the Joint Committee for the cutting departments of the Dress Manufacturing Industry for the Province of Quebec, and meeting minutes of the Montreal Joint Board’s Educational Committee.
    - 5780/116. Montreal Joint Board records, 1930-1981., Contains the records of the ILGWU’s Montreal Joint Board Dressmakers Union and the Montreal Joint Council Cloakmakers Union, as well as Montreal’s Joint Committee of the Ladies’ Cloak and Suit Industry. These records include meeting announcements and minutes, correspondence with local members and ILGWU leadership, and draft and final agreements. Also contains material on the following local unions: 19, 43, 61, 112, 113, 205, 207, 241, 245, 246, 247, 248, 262, 263, 315, 342, 421, 422, 438, 439, 481, 485, 521.
  - Subseries B. District Councils and Regional Departments, 1901-2000
    - 5780/038. Canadian Area films, 1958-1975., Films generated and collected by Canadian locals of the International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union.
    - 5780/090. Central Pennsylvania District records, 1956-1985., This collection is almost entirely comprised of publications either published or collected by the Central Pennsylvania District. This includes a substantial run of the district’s periodical, The Garment Worker (1956-1975), as well as a variety of publications from labor organizations in Pennsylvania and throughout the northeastern United States.
    - 5780/090 P. Central Pennsylvania District photographs, This collection contains photographs documenting the activities of the members and staff of the Central Pennsylvania District. Included are photographs of union activities such strikes, rallies, meetings, and conventions, as well as classes, social gatherings, trips to Unity House, and others.
    - 5780/101. Midwest Region records, 1911-1996., Collection contains charters, correspondence, agreements, printed material, and memorabilia of the office of the Midwest Region of the International Ladies’ Garment Workers’ Union. Two series of correspondence (one alphabetical, another chronological) and collective bargaining agreements constitute the bulk of the collection. Several Midwest Region local unions are represented in the records: 5, 18, 59, 76, 100, 191, 240, 261, 272, 303, 326, 336, 337, 355, 373, 395, 436, 442, 455, 488, 505, 527.
    - 5780/101 AV. Midwest Region audio-visual materials, 1988-1996., This collection contains audio-visual material that was either produced by or featured the ILGWU. Included are videos from ILGWU conventions and videos about the garment industry in the United States.
    - 5780/050. Northeast Department records, 1940-1970., The first box of this collection contains the diaries (1950-1959) of David Gingold noting meetings, conferences, and important phone conversations, as well as the appointment books (1950-1970) of David Gingold scheduling trips, conferences, meetings, luncheons and holidays. The second box contains the speeches and statements (1944-1960) made by David Gingold, and publications of the Northeast Department.
    - 5780/183. Ohio-Kentucky Region records, 1960-1999., Contains material relating to the activities of the office of the Ohio Kentucky region, minutes of local union 300 between 1964 and 1968, and resolutions passed by city and state governments in the region in recognition of Garment Workers’ Day, 1975. Also contains printed material either published or collected by the office, including the Ohio Kentucky Region periodical, Ohio Kentucky News from 1960 to 1977.
    - 5780/183 AV. Ohio-Kentucky Region audio-visual Materials., This collection contains motion picture film, film strips, and reel-to-reel audio tapes created by or for the Ohio-Kentucky Region. Included in the collection is documentation of a convention, and educational, cultural, and recreational activities.
    - 5780/183 P. Ohio-Kentucky Region photographs., This collection consists of photographs transferred from the Ohio Kentucky Region records. Photographs document the activities of the regional department, including meetings, rallies, and conventions. Some photographs appear to have been used in the Ohio Kentucky Region periodical, Ohio Kentucky News.
    - 5780/207. Pacific Northwest District Council records, 1944-2000., Contains meeting minutes from several unions that constituted the district (locals 8, 101, 213, 214, and 215), as well as the meeting minutes of the San Francisco Joint Board and the Pacific Northwest District Council, financial statements of district funds, and board meeting materials of the Bay Area Health, Welfare Fund. Also contains correspondence files of managers of the Pacific Northwest District Council, Mattie Jackson and Katie Quan, files pertaining to organizing efforts; especially well-represented are campaigns at Kong’s Knitwear/Elegant Knits (San Francisco) and San Francisco Knitworks in the 1990s.
    - 5780/207. Pacific Northwest District Council audio-visual materials, Consists of an audio cassette recording of an undated San Francisco Council meeting.
    - 5780/207 P. Pacific Northwest District Council photographs, 1989-1993., This collection consists of photographs transferred from the records of the Pacific Northwest District Council. Included are photographs of a rally against NAFTA, meetings, and other union events.
    - 5780/204. Pennsylvania records, 1951-1995., Contains files on several local unions, district councils, and district departments in Pennsylvania. Especially well-documented are the organizing efforts of Northeastern Pennsylvania’s Stakeholder Alliance and the 1994 strike of Leslie Fay in Wilkes-Barre, Pennsylvania. Records relating to the ILGWU chorus may be found in the files on local union 295 and the Wyoming Valley District. Also contains meeting minutes of local union 295, local 249 and 327, and the Hazleton District Council.
    - 5780/117. Quebec Joint Council records, 1962-1987., Contains council by-laws, correspondence, clippings, subject files, and material relating to council conventions between 1981 and 1987.
    - 5780/058. Southeast Region records, 1937-1970., Contains general chronological correspondence (1951-1966), weekly reports from organizers (1959-1960, 1972-1974), and alphabetical subject files. Among these alphabetical subject files are agreements (1946-1960), files on David Dubinsky (1947-1968), regional reports to the GEB (1947-1962), records of the regional office’s political department (1948-1969), and material pertaining to the annual regional conference (1953-1969). Locals represented in the records of the Southeast Region include: 10, 23-25, 25, 62, 91 and 105 (New York, NY), 122 (Atlanta, GA), 375 (Birmingham, AL), 378 (Flagg-Utica), 457 (Cullman, AL), 473, and 574.
    - 5780/058 AV. Southeast Region audio recordings, 1975-1979., This collection contains audio recordings of the Southeast Region’s conferences in 1978 and 1979, as well as audio recordings of speeches and Union Label songs.
    - 5780/039. Upper South Department records, 1937-1971., Contains records of the Upper South Department of the International Ladies’ Garment Workers’ Union, including correspondence, agreements, financial statements, and many files on joint boards, local unions, and conferences in the region. Joint Boards of Baltimore, Cleveland, and New York City are represented in the records of the Upper South Department.
    - 5780/120. Western Massachusetts District records, 1937-1971., Contains records of the Western Massachusetts District Council primarily documenting its financial transactions, including records of state and federal tax payments, documentation of investments, fundraising for its Campaign Committee, and benefits paid from the Northeast Department Health and Welfare Fund. A smaller portion of the Western District Council records is correspondence on other matters.
    - 5780/115. Western States Region records, 1949-1975., Contains records of the office of the Western States Region’s constitutive departments, namely Political and Education, Organizing, Legal Services, and Accounting and Miscellaneous Services. Contains an extensive series of papers from Cornelius Wall (Director, Western States Region), Max Wolf (Director, Political and Education Department), Ralph Smith (Director, Organizing Department) and Smith’s successor, Meyer Silverstein (Director, Organizing Department). Also contains reports of house calls to prospective ILGWU members in records from the Organizing Department (boxes 80, 81, 87) and Cornelius Wall (box 94). Includes substantial records of arbitrations, cases before the National Labor Relations Board, and company files. Dispersed throughout the records are files on all of the joint boards and district councils (Los Angeles Joint Board, San Francisco Joint Board, Arizona-Utah District Council, Southern California District Council) as well as individual locals (in Oregon and Washington) that fell under the purview of the Western States. However, activities in California are more fully represented than other areas of the Western States Region.
- SERIES III. LOCAL UNIONS, 1901-1996
  - ASSORTED LOCALS
    - 5780/037. Locals minutes, 1913-1962., Includes meeting minutes of Local 29 (Boston), Local 56 and 24 (Boston), Local 69 (Philadelphia), and Local 177 (New York).
    - 5780/195 PUBS. Local publications, 1935-1948., Contains issues of The Emancipator, which began as the publication of local 187 in 1936; became the publication of locals 187, local 188, and local 273 in 1938; and eventually the publication of the Milwaukee Joint Board (locals 187, 188, 273, 292, and 334). In addition to coverage of Milwaukee and national news, The Emancipator covered other Wisconsin locals: Raincoat Makers’ Union 374 (La Cross, then later, Wausau), Cotton Dress Makers’ Union 379 (La Crosse), Garments Workers’ Unions 381 (Chippewa), Raincoat Makers Union 322 (Milwaukee?), Sportswear Union 325 (Baraboo), Cotton Dress Workers 417 (Watertown), Knitgoods Workers’ Union 432 (Delevan), Underwear Workers’ Union 450 (New London), Sportswear (later Raincoat) Workers Union 464 (Stoughton), Sportswear Workers Union 503 (Stoughton), Cotton Dress Workers’ Union 508 (Mauston).
  - MONTREAL, QUEBEC
    - 5780/025. Local 262 minutes, 1943-1970., Consists of minutes from Local 262’s Executive Board, Membership, Pressers Branch, and Welfare Fund Committee meetings.
    - 5780/026. Local 315 minutes, 1937-1963., Consists of minutes of Local 315’s Executive Board and Membership meetings.
    - 5780/027. Local 205 minutes, 1935-1967., Consists of minutes of Local 205’s Executive Board and General Membership meetings.
    - 5780/028. Montreal locals minutes, 1936-1974., Records of the International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union Locals 19, 43, 61, 112, 342, 438, 584, and 592. Included are meeting minutes and correspondence.
  - NEW YORK, NEW YORK
    - 5780/013. Local 9. Managers' correspondence, 1933-1951., Consists of the correspondence of managers Isidore Sorkin and Louis Hyman of Local 9 of the International Ladies’ Garment Workers’ Union. Includes correspondence with several departments of the Cloak Joint Board and the office of the President of the International Ladies’ Garment Workers’ Union.
    - 5780/017. Local 9. Executive Board and Grievance Committee minutes, 1914-1944., Minute books of Local 9 of the International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union for the years 1914-1944 and periodicals from the 43rd Convention of the Workmen’s Circle in 1943.
    - 5780/017 P. Local 9. Executive Board and Grievance Committee photographs, 1914-1944., This collection consists of one photograph including Joe Gregory, Charlie Kaplan, Albert Rogers, and Mary Newman.
    - 5780/001. Local 10 minutes, 1906-1973., This collection contains executive board minutes and calendars, membership meeting minutes, and division minutes of the International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union, Local 10, the Amalgamated Ladies’ Garment Cutters Union. Also contains miscellaneous records of Locals 10, 23, and 25, including files on special meetings, membership committees, and companies.
    - 5780/001mf. Local 10 minutes, 1911-1971. Microfilm., This collection contains minutes of Local 10's Executive Board meetings.
    - 5780/008. Local 10. Amalgamated Ladies Garment Cutters Union. Dues books, 1904-1911., Dues books of Amalgamated Ladies' Garment Cutters' Union, Local 10 of the International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union. Two ledgers include alphabetical listings of 2,196 members, and a third ledger, for the year 1903, is indexed.
    - 5780/011. Local 10. Managers' correspondence, 1942-1968., This collection contains correspondence of Isidore Nagler and Moe Falikman. Nagler was Manager of the Amalgamated Ladies' Garment Cutters' Union, Local 10 of the International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union from 1939 to 1952. Falikman succeeded him, serving as manager from 1953 to 1968.
    - 5780/012. Local 10. Managers' correspondence, 1952-1968., Correspondence of Isidore Nagler, Manager of the Amalgamated Ladies' Garment Cutters' Union, Local 10 of the International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union.
    - 5780/094. Local 10 membership record book, 1911-1915., This collection consists of a book of membership records for International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union Local 10, Amalgamated Ladies' Garment Cutters' Union. Also included are three spreadsheets and one death benefits assignment letter.
    - 5780/131. Local 10 records, 1971., Contains records documenting elections of local union officers. Included are files relating to Harry Shaw’s protest and appeal to Local 10’s Election and Objection Committtee and, eventually, to the National Labor Relations Board. Shaw was candidate for the office of Secretary of the Executive Board in 1971.
    - 5780/014. Local 22. Charles Zimmerman papers, 1919-1958, 1920-1945 (bulk)., The Charles Zimmerman papers consist primarily of correspondence, reports, minutes, newspaper clippings, and broadsides dealing with his activities as a leader in Local 22 (in Series I), as well as his other union and political activities (in Series II). Among the most significant material in the collection is correspondence documenting Zimmerman's activities with the Communist Party in the U.S. and its various factions and splinter groups, as well as other political organizations and figures. Correspondents include Jay Lovestone and William Z. Foster; there is also considerable material dealing with the Communist Party of the U.S.A. and the "Majority Group," or Lovestone faction. Other political parties represented include the American Labor Party, the Liberal Party (New York State), and the Socialist Party.
    - 5780/014 P. Local 22. Charles Zimmerman photographs, 1910-1958., The collection includes images of important people and events in Local 22 including ILGWU President David Dubinsky, Local 22 Manager Charles Zimmerman, Max Danish, Fania Cohn, Rose Pesotta, and Maida Springer Kemp, along with images of sports and cultural events, parades, marches, strikes, meetings and educational programs.
    - 5780/015. Local 22 records, 1920-1933., Collection consists of alphabetical files of Local 22 from 1920 to 1933, containing correspondence, memoranda, minutes, and other material.
    - 5780/036. Local 22 minutes, 1934-1972., Records of International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union Local 22, Dressmakers Union. Includes minutes of Executive Board, Membership, and Grievance Committee meetings.
    - 5780/057. Local 22. Education Department records, 1933-1975, 1950-1970 (bulk)., The records of the Education Department of Local 22, New York City are made up of correspondence, newspaper clippings, newsletters, programs, photographs, and speeches documenting the activities of the Department from the 1930s to the 1970s. In addition to documentation of the Department's activities, there is material on the local's political involvement with the Liberal Party of New York State and some items about aid to the Republican cause during the Spanish Civil War. There are also some materials dealing with international labor cooperation, civil rights, and communism in the U.S. Correspondents include Joseph Mazur and Saby Nehama.